I have screwed a lot with drag racing when I was younger, kind of promod.
Also screwed up a bit with snowmobile drag racing.
I've always liked drag racing.
-What is you competing with?
Should we check what you have.
We can start with the veteran class.
Then you can have one here.
Sure you can have a finer but I have chosen it to look a little worn.
-Lite Rat Rod?
Yes.
Mechanically, it is in top condition.
All brakes and layers are replaced.
It is very nice condition even though it is not visible.
-70 numbers?
No all mopeds I have are 66or.
Sport Combinette 1966.
So it is -66 that applies?
Yes right now ...
I have a little newer too.
It is possible to stroke up to 72cc.
-What does it cost to trim?
Is it expensive?
Both yes and no.
It is a cheap sport to be motorsport.
Motorsport costs money but this is cheap.
I crashed a motor a week ago.
The block burst and the gearbox ...
It cost SEK 2500 to cook.
-Oh!
A little drive and shoulders then you can drive again.
A car engine that breaks can cost SEK 75,000 to cook.
Absolutely!
Or more.
This one I bought far out in the woods a few miles from here.
-Do you run 200 meters?
Yes, 200 meters with a stationary start.
-How many gears do you have?
This one has four.
3-4 years ago, 3 drove.
It was such a big step between 2an and 3an.
It is not suitable for drag racing.
Not if you are going to perform good times.
What I remembered from when I was young.
Now I didn't have Zundapp myself ...
... was that the gear slider had a long stroke.
Yes you hit the knee in the elbow.
That is why we who compete have gear stops.
-The gear stop?
I can't give all the mopeds love between the runs.
One or two is recommended.
-How very screw is it vs run?
Hmm ... change drives and nozzles ..
..The rusty I have been running so many years so I almost do not screw it.
Just pushed up a cog last time and it was probably the only thing.
This requires ignition adjustment, mouth cut ... ... there are so many adjustments left.
It can take 10 hours of driving before it goes 90% of its capacity.
The rusty is probably 100% of its capacity.
It is almost not possible to drive anything faster with it.
It is difficult.
But this is much left.
This one should go faster than the rusty but it does not.
It's a long way to go yet.
I have chosen to run a Zundapp engine on this with.
-What does a modern engine mean?
Yes you can have 6-gears.
Most of them are reed -fed original.
It is awesome and lightly trimmed engines.
This is a little more complicated.
-You hold you to Zundapp.
It would be to put on an AM6 engine on this.
Then I would rather get further down in the field.
This is a promod 50, ie 50cc.
The rusty is 66cc in the veteran 70 class.
This one is quite exactly 70cc in the same class.
And this Promod 50 and it is about 50cc.
We are not dissected, they think it is cool so I hope more will start competing.
-What is the most fun to drive?
Right now it's the rusty one because it delivers.
After all, it is tested to the max.
The other two I have a lot of work left.
-Both?
Yes both.
I tested it chassis last year and had this engine on.
Just to test the chassis and then I used this engine a polini that I ported myself.
I drove 10.3 and 105-106 km/h with that engine.
In this chassis and then I discovered that it had to be strengthened.
Trying to build as easily as possible but ...
... that engine twisted the entire chassis.
The chassis was too clumsy so I had to reinforce.
Last year you can say that chassis work well.
This year I have used the real engine but ...
... I have had problems with.
It sounds strange and I have scrapped some membrane and blown packing boxes when I drive nitrous oxide.
This is how there is ...
-How many people drive with nitrous oxide on mopeds?
Yes there are some pieces ...
... there are also those who drive with nitro in promod.
And those who drive with methanol.
It is quite unlimited in Promod.
-How is the buddy at the competitions?
It is very good.
-Ing hard rivalry?
No, it's a nice level.
There is no prestige.
Everyone knows everyone and we have fun in the evenings.
-You don't reveal your secrets?
A little bit so maybe, gate times etc ..
-When you trim do everything yourself?
I try to do everything myself.
I have built some pipes but have not got it really well.
Recently, I have bought ready -made that I have modified.
Contracted header, shortened and extended and made adjustments.
So that it hangs like a snake in the ceiling.
Yes a little different pipes that I have tried over the years.
-How long holds a piston & cylinder?
That .. you talk about the rusty, huh?
I have been running it for 2 years and I changed piston ring this spring that's all.
Although it turns so much so it holds well.
-What is this?
It looks like...
Here I usually sit and port cylinders.
Isn't this a goldsmith usually use?
Well, it's from an old workshop.
It is a little small sometimes and I have not been able to port coil.
Now I have found this and I think it is from the 60s.
It is old dental equipment.
Now I come down in the cylinders so I can change the coil.
-Where can you find such old stuff?
Think it was at Tradera.
You had one more moped over here is it also a Zundapp?
Yes it is a ride moped completely original.
Okay a utility lashes.
-Is there any moped we can start?
Can start any.
We can start up the rusty.
Don't think people understand that there is a lot to drive when it looks like it does.
Absolutely, pick it up.
-Do you nice on that one?
No!
I usually train a lot of starts and get abrasions the inside of the thighs.
So it is not nice but all for the look.
14400 rpm.
Well I have alternated more sometimes.
Now it's cold so I don't want to torment it.
Damn!
Which moped.
There are some in Ö-vik, Lycksele and Bjäst.
Great name!
Easy.
Hahaha!
It sounds like a cross.
16320 rpm, it's totally crazy.
-This is like a cross.
Yes the light is deceiving.
Hahaha, really!
It's totally crazy.
I didn't get the camera when you drove past.
A little missed gears when it is not a sharp position and you have foppa slippers.
Normally, the gears sit as they should.
Not many people do not think it should go fast when you see it.
It usually is so.
It has a lovely sound.
Yes it is straight in the clutch basket.
So it wines a little neighbor.
What a machine!
-How should you go if you want to start competing?
There are 2 pages on the Internet and Facebook.
Facebook: Swedish Moped Dragracing and Lyckseletwostroke.se
There you can read and ask questions.
Check out past events.
Then I think you should start competing.
There are so many sharp mopeds ...